<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<post>
  <author>johan</author>
  <title>Cross publishing by mirroring, or?</title>
  <description />
  <content>&lt;h2&gt;The requirements&lt;/h2&gt;  &lt;p&gt;One of our clients has an enterprise solution with several websites in the same EPiServer database and wanted to be able to publish some content just once and then the content would be reflected on each website. But sometimes they wanted to create local content as well in the same page structure which was created by the global content. Sometimes parts of the content shouldn’t be reflected on all sites, just selected ones.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The two latter requirements made the solution much more complex.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;[more]&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;h2&gt;The solution&lt;/h2&gt;  &lt;p&gt;If it wasn’t for the requirement to create local content too, the obvious solution would be a custom &lt;em&gt;Page Provider&lt;/em&gt;. So we started to investigate if mirroring suited our needs.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;We created a site called &lt;em&gt;Global Content&lt;/em&gt; which holds all the global content and then three test websites. Then we installed the mirroring service as a stand-alone application. We &lt;a href="http://world.episerver.com/Documentation/Items/Tech-Notes/EPiServer-CMS-6/EPiServer-CMS-60/Mirroring/"&gt;configured&lt;/a&gt; the mirroring service.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;We created a couple of mirroring channels and ran the scheduled job. It all worked just fine. Then we tested to create local pages where the mirroring service already created some pages, created some more global pages and then ran the job again. Everything worked just fine.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;To meet the requirement that not all sites should receive all, let’s say news articles, the editor could categorize the articles and then the news archive page just listed the selected categories.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;In production, the number of websites increased to about 10 and now we had about 30 mirroring channels. Things started to go bad. The mirroring service froze and the CPU utilized 100%! After a while we received a timeout. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“The request channel timed out while waiting for a reply after 00:01:00. Increase the timeout value passed to the call to Request or increase the SendTimeout value on the Binding. The time allotted to this operation may have been a portion of a longer timeout.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The error message suggested to beef up the timeout, so we did. But no luck there. We started to fiddle with all the other settings. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dodavinkeln.se/image.axd?picture=image.png"&gt;&lt;img class="left" alt="" src="http://www.dodavinkeln.se/image.axd?picture=image_thumb.png" width="244" height="168" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;We noted there were a lot of requests to the service, and long lived ones. We read some &lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/tmarq/archive/2007/07/21/asp-net-thread-usage-on-iis-7-0-and-6-0.aspx"&gt;articles about number of concurrent requests&lt;/a&gt; and changed the MaxConcurrentRequestsPerCPU to 5000.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The developer support suggested some other changes, like closeTimeout, openTimeout, receiveTimeout, sendTimeout and maxConnections on the binding configuration.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;One thing to note is that there wasn’t much content which was mirrored, it seemed to be the number of channels that was causing the error. But we decreased the numberOfPagesInPackage setting.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Nothing seemed to work.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;We also received “Error while unloading appdomain. (Exception from HRESULT: 0x80131015)” and “Exception: The ConnectionString property has not been initialized.[]”.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Now we started to disable some channels so we were down to about 20 channels. Now the job started to work again, sometimes it even ran fast.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;OK, so mirroring doesn’t seem to work so well if you’re mirroring to the same server with a lot of channels. Now we looked in to do our custom scheduled job and execute each channel with some timespan between them, but after some digging with reflector that seemed like a huge task.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;So this wasn’t the solution after all. But it will work in some cases, and will probably be one part of our final solution where the target content should be exactly as the source but the editor should be able to create local pages.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;I remembered an old &lt;a href="http://world.episerver.com/Blogs/Anders-Hattestad/Dates/2011/1/PageProviders-and-DDS-a-match-from-heaven/"&gt;article from Anders Hattestad&lt;/a&gt; in which he used the &lt;em&gt;DDS&lt;/em&gt; and created a &lt;em&gt;Page Provider&lt;/em&gt; for local pages. Stay tuned for part 2 in this mini series, where we create a more sophisticated &lt;em&gt;Page Provider&lt;/em&gt; with some more settings.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>True</ispublished>
  <iscommentsenabled>True</iscommentsenabled>
  <pubDate>2012-02-09 10:36:00</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2012-02-09 15:39:20</lastModified>
  <raters>0</raters>
  <rating>0</rating>
  <slug>cross-publishing-by-mirroring</slug>
  <tags>
    <tag>cross-publishing</tag>
    <tag>mirroring</tag>
  </tags>
  <comments>
    <comment id="0dcb798a-d5be-485d-8fca-216ed119f0ef" parentid="00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000" approved="True">
      <date>2013-06-11 19:52:20</date>
      <author>neverwinter ad</author>
      <email>krhdiyozhru@aol.com</email>
      <country />
      <ip>1.165.127.22</ip>
      <website>http://www.astraldiamondsneverwinter.com/</website>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;i just picked up most of these neverwinter ad through saying my family and i lost control inlove together your current free my wife and i experienced all of them! many feature these types of in addition to repeat the end creases below my verizon prepaid phone hasn't ever made that even though the tab around the proper neverwinter ad doesnt may appear on the grounds that business even though the kept only one yet somehow really they may be ultimate hopefully this valuable aided&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    </comment>
    <comment id="be5eff1e-456f-4bf0-b933-4395d1d17d92" parentid="00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000" approved="True">
      <date>2013-09-06 14:32:11</date>
      <author>background Check</author>
      <email>blairbeaudoin@t-online.de</email>
      <country />
      <ip>177.135.221.218</ip>
      <website>http://criminal-background-check-free.com/</website>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I am really delighted to read this blog posts which contains tons of helpful data, thanks for providing such &lt;br /&gt;information.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    </comment>
    <comment id="8914806f-b808-4243-82ec-9290a7aecfcf" parentid="00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000" approved="True">
      <date>2013-09-06 14:36:58</date>
      <author>freecreditscore.com</author>
      <email>bessmoody@gmail.com</email>
      <country />
      <ip>177.135.221.218</ip>
      <website>http://freefreecreditscore.org/</website>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Heya this is kind of of off topic but I was wondering if &lt;br /&gt;blogs use WYSIWYG editors or if you have to &lt;br /&gt;manually code with HTML. I'm starting a blog soon but have no &lt;br /&gt;coding skills so I wanted to get guidance from someone with experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Any help would be enormously appreciated!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    </comment>
    <comment id="8c65bd8e-b136-4287-9390-a34d92864dec" parentid="00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000" approved="True">
      <date>2013-09-06 14:37:39</date>
      <author>background check companies</author>
      <email>charlie-steward@gmail.com</email>
      <country />
      <ip>177.135.221.218</ip>
      <website>http://been--verified.com/</website>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Hello, I believe your blog might be having internet browser &lt;br /&gt;compatibility issues. Whenever I look at your web site in Safari, it &lt;br /&gt;looks fine however, when opening in I.E., it has some &lt;br /&gt;overlapping issues. I merely wanted to provide you &lt;br /&gt;with a quick heads up! Aside from that, great site!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    </comment>
    <comment id="57b4cd6f-3684-472c-be15-52e2af6cae97" parentid="00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000" approved="True">
      <date>2013-09-06 14:39:18</date>
      <author>free background checks criminal records</author>
      <email>thalia_walton@gmx.net</email>
      <country />
      <ip>177.135.221.218</ip>
      <website>http://check--background.com/</website>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;That is very fascinating, You are an overly professional blogger.&lt;br /&gt;I have joined your rss feed and look forward to in the hunt for extra of your fantastic post.&lt;br /&gt;Also, I've shared your web site in my social networks&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    </comment>
    <comment id="b046fc7c-3781-4cd1-af0d-90521214f992" parentid="00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000" approved="True">
      <date>2013-09-06 14:40:00</date>
      <author>free background check</author>
      <email>daverasmussen@gmail.com</email>
      <country />
      <ip>177.135.221.218</ip>
      <website>http://humbermedia.com/article/index.php?a=stats&amp;u=mikkibumgarner</website>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I am actually glad to read this weebpage posts which contains tons of valuable data, tganks &lt;br /&gt;for providing thedse kinds of statistics.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    </comment>
    <comment id="6af5aba8-592e-4a38-8327-c988ae927239" parentid="00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000" approved="True">
      <date>2013-09-06 14:41:10</date>
      <author>Dawn</author>
      <email>dawnreitz@googlemail.com</email>
      <country />
      <ip>177.135.221.218</ip>
      <website>http://lending--tree.com/</website>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Hi! Quick question that's entirely off topic. Do you &lt;br /&gt;know how to make your site mobile friendly?&lt;br /&gt;My website looks weird when viewing from my iphone. I'm trying to find a theme &lt;br /&gt;or plugin that might be able to correct this problem.&lt;br /&gt;If you have any recommendations, please share.&lt;br /&gt;Many thanks!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    </comment>
    <comment id="82aef1f6-3258-4ee9-baad-7c17e7cd8d83" parentid="00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000" approved="True">
      <date>2013-09-06 14:42:01</date>
      <author>credit ratings</author>
      <email>teresitacorcoran@inbox.com</email>
      <country />
      <ip>177.135.221.218</ip>
      <website>http://freefreecreditreport.org/</website>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I blog often and I genuinely thank you for your content. This great &lt;br /&gt;article has really peaked my interest. I'm going to take a note of &lt;br /&gt;your website and keep checking for new information &lt;br /&gt;about once a week. I opted in for your Feed as well.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    </comment>
    <comment id="36d0da47-5dbf-4623-b458-5ba69628f83d" parentid="00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000" approved="True">
      <date>2013-09-06 14:42:55</date>
      <author>credit history</author>
      <email>kristophersparks@peacemail.com</email>
      <country />
      <ip>177.135.221.218</ip>
      <website>http://a-free-credit-score.com/</website>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Nice post. I was checking constantly this blog &lt;br /&gt;and I am impressed! Extremely useful info specially the last part :&lt;br /&gt;) I care for such information a lot. I was looking for this particular &lt;br /&gt;info for a long time. Thank you and good luck.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    </comment>
    <comment id="a132fe28-93d4-4941-8495-cc46e5fc53fb" parentid="00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000" approved="True">
      <date>2013-09-06 14:43:19</date>
      <author>free criminal check</author>
      <email>mittie.schwab@gmail.com</email>
      <country />
      <ip>177.135.221.218</ip>
      <website>http://websiteranktool.com/background--check.net</website>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I know this if off topic but I'm looking into starting my &lt;br /&gt;own blog and was curious what all is needed to get setup?&lt;br /&gt;I'm assuming having a blog like yours would cost a pretty penny?&lt;br /&gt;I'm not very internet smart so I'm not 100% sure.&lt;br /&gt;Any recommendations or advice would be greatly appreciated.&lt;br /&gt;Thank you&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    </comment>
    <comment id="b2dbb657-8ca3-4248-bcb0-cc8829366b1a" parentid="00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000" approved="True">
      <date>2013-09-06 14:43:41</date>
      <author>Rocco</author>
      <email>roccoskelton@gmail.com</email>
      <country />
      <ip>177.135.221.218</ip>
      <website>http://facialskin-care.net/</website>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;You really make it seem so easy with your presentation &lt;br /&gt;but I to find this matter to be really something that I believe &lt;br /&gt;I'd never understand. It seems too complex and extremely large for me.&lt;br /&gt;I am looking forward for your subsequent publish, I will attempt &lt;br /&gt;to get the grasp of it!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    </comment>
    <comment id="412ec52f-6601-4d7b-9a7b-0ccde75f1160" parentid="00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000" approved="True">
      <date>2013-09-06 14:43:53</date>
      <author>Jeremy</author>
      <email>jeremy.mccormick@gmail.com</email>
      <country />
      <ip>177.135.221.218</ip>
      <website>http://what-isresveratrol.com/</website>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;My brother recommended I would possibly like this website.&lt;br /&gt;He was entirely right. This put up actually made my day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can not believe simply how a lot time I had spent for this info!&lt;br /&gt;Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    </comment>
    <comment id="443b658d-4481-4783-8729-226957a1736b" parentid="00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000" approved="True">
      <date>2013-09-06 14:44:21</date>
      <author>credit Rating check</author>
      <email>maitovar@live.com</email>
      <country />
      <ip>177.135.221.218</ip>
      <website>http://free--creditreport.org/</website>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever thought about adding a little bit more than just your articles?&lt;br /&gt;I mean, what you say is valuable and all. Nevertheless think about if you added some great pictures or video &lt;br /&gt;clips to give your posts more, "pop"! Your content is excellent but with images and clips, this website could &lt;br /&gt;definitely be one of the very best in its field.&lt;br /&gt;Awesome blog!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    </comment>
    <comment id="e50ba5f6-94ec-48f0-8113-f3333c42e69c" parentid="00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000" approved="True">
      <date>2013-09-06 14:44:40</date>
      <author>thalgo Skin care</author>
      <email>rudy.chisholm@gawab.com</email>
      <country />
      <ip>177.135.221.218</ip>
      <website>http://whatisresveratrol.net/</website>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;We are a group of volunteers and starting a brand new scheme in our community.&lt;br /&gt;Your web site provided us with useful info to work on.&lt;br /&gt;You've performed a formidable task and our whole neighborhood will likely &lt;br /&gt;be grateful to you.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    </comment>
    <comment id="b32470c6-a80d-415f-8b5d-a14075475705" parentid="00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000" approved="True">
      <date>2013-09-06 14:45:21</date>
      <author>credit reports</author>
      <email>jeremygoode@web.de</email>
      <country />
      <ip>177.135.221.218</ip>
      <website>http://my-creditreport.net/</website>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;This design is incredible! You most certainly know how to &lt;br /&gt;keep a reader amused. Betwen yojr wit and your videos, I was almost moved to start my own blog (well, almost...HaHa!) Great job.&lt;br /&gt;I really enjoyed what you had too say, aand more than that, how you presented it.&lt;br /&gt;Too cool!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    </comment>
    <comment id="e6b9e84a-6199-42b7-9363-6adf7f218d2d" parentid="00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000" approved="True">
      <date>2013-09-06 14:49:08</date>
      <author>been verified</author>
      <email>georgianamiddleton@zoho.com</email>
      <country />
      <ip>177.135.221.218</ip>
      <website>http://background--checks.org/</website>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;May I simply say what a relief to uncover somebody that truly understands &lt;br /&gt;what they are talking about on the net. You definitely realize how to bring &lt;br /&gt;an issue to light and make it important. More and more people have to read this and &lt;br /&gt;understand this side of the story. I was surprised that you are &lt;br /&gt;not more popular because you definitely have the gift.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    </comment>
    <comment id="c0edd9b8-0898-4b31-9271-c5615940e795" parentid="00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000" approved="True">
      <date>2013-09-06 14:51:24</date>
      <author>Princess</author>
      <email>princesstreadwell@gmail.com</email>
      <country />
      <ip>177.135.221.218</ip>
      <website>http://my-credit-report.org/</website>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Attractive section of content. I just stumbled upon your &lt;br /&gt;blog and in accession capital to say that I get in fact enjoyed account your weblog posts.&lt;br /&gt;Any way I'll be subscribing in your feeds and even I fulfillment you get admission to persistently fast.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    </comment>
    <comment id="b7a39cfb-2577-4643-bd59-a050bbd77595" parentid="00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000" approved="True">
      <date>2013-09-06 14:51:39</date>
      <author>webpage</author>
      <email>susanafitzpatrick@gmail.com</email>
      <country />
      <ip>177.135.221.218</ip>
      <website>http://ngbot.com/criminal-background-check-free.com</website>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;This is a topic that is close to my heart...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take care! Where arre your contact details though?&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    </comment>
    <comment id="379d5bcd-8336-4832-a2d2-daf9a8add503" parentid="00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000" approved="True">
      <date>2013-09-06 14:52:05</date>
      <author>background search free</author>
      <email>ana-otero@gmail.com</email>
      <country />
      <ip>177.135.221.218</ip>
      <website>http://been-verified.net/</website>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I do agree with all the ideas you have introduced &lt;br /&gt;on your post. They're really convincing and will certainly work.&lt;br /&gt;Still, the posts are very brief for newbies. Could you please lengthen them a &lt;br /&gt;little from next time? Thank you for the post.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    </comment>
    <comment id="1283a9dc-97b0-498f-a677-4d4d7c23ad42" parentid="00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000" approved="True">
      <date>2013-09-06 14:53:07</date>
      <author>faxless payday loans</author>
      <email>lorrainekendall@gawab.com</email>
      <country />
      <ip>177.135.221.218</ip>
      <website>http://car--loan.org/</website>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I believe this is among the most vital information for me.&lt;br /&gt;And i'm glad reading your article. However should remark on some &lt;br /&gt;normal things, The website taste is perfect, the articles is truly excellent : D.&lt;br /&gt;Good task, cheers&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    </comment>
    <comment id="6beb782d-10fc-405e-8463-0678a3bf38e5" parentid="00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000" approved="True">
      <date>2013-09-19 14:19:06</date>
      <author>Audra Gooding</author>
      <email>jeapchiiit@gmail.com</email>
      <country />
      <ip>200.84.8.115</ip>
      <website>http://my.telegraph.co.uk/areyeastinfectionscontagious/</website>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever thought about adding a little bit more than just your articles? I mean, what you say is fundamental and everything. Nevertheless imagine if you added some great images or videos to give your posts more, "pop"! Your content is excellent but with images and videos, this site could certainly be one of the best in its field. Wonderful blog!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    </comment>
    <comment id="90a05aef-6884-4e3a-a2c4-ef49401a3c2b" parentid="00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000" approved="True">
      <date>2013-10-07 19:21:04</date>
      <author>for rent</author>
      <email>stacey_macaluso@hotmail.de</email>
      <country />
      <ip>151.237.186.52</ip>
      <website>http://wikijava.org.ua/index.php?title=The_Very_"Ins_And_Outs"_Of_Short</website>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Hi! Do you know if they make any plugins to help with Search Engine &lt;br /&gt;Optimization? I'm trying to get my blog to rank for some targeted keywords but I'm not seeing very good gains.&lt;br /&gt;If you know of any please share. Appreciate it!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <categories>
    <category>bf74dc56-651d-4a32-89bf-d757b885fc05</category>
  </categories>
  <notifications>
    <email>melaagya175064@gmail.com</email>
  </notifications>
</post>